Guide to the George A. Lindbeck Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Collected Materials: General, nd; Series IX
  - re: Social: "Voyage of the Psychenauts: A Report on a Journey Inside the Mind" by Kenneth Cavander in Harper's, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 1277)
  - re: Social: "Global Pluralism" by Diane Ravitch in Commentary, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 1278)
  - re: Social: "Social Research" in Religion in the Sixties, nd (Box 54, Folder 1279)
  - re: Saints: "St. Thomas and Platonism" by W. Norris Clarke in Thought, v. XXXII, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 1280)
  - re: Saints: "Scientia Dei and Scientia Divina: A Reformulation of Thomas Aquinas" by Victor Stephen Preller, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 1281)
  - re: Saints: "The Theory of Signs in St. Augustine's De Doctrina Christiana " by B. Darrell Jackson in Revue des Etudes Augustiniennes, 1969 (Box 54, Folder 1282)
  - re: Saints: "Dear Norvin" by Charles Walls in Reflections, 1986 (Box 54, Folder 1283)
  - re: Saints: "Saint Anselm: Ontological Proof", nd (Box 54, Folder 1284)
  - re: Theology: "Korean Theologian Pays Price for Her Convictions" in The Lutheran, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 1285)
  - re: Tillich: "The Theological Significance of Paul Tillich" by Gustave Weigel in Cross Currents, nd (Box 54, Folder 1286)
  - re: Wittgenstein: "Wittgenstein and Descriptive Theology" by Richard H. Bell in Religious Studies (Box 54, Folder 1287)
  - re: Woolman: "Inwardness and Outward Concerns: A Study of John Woolman's Thought" by William A. Christian in Quaker History, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 1288)
  - Miscellaneous, nd (Box 54, Folder 1289)
  - Writings of: Ambrogi, Tom; Bellah, Robert N.; Benton, Matthew A.; Bernstein, Richard; Burghardt, Walter; Carter, J. Kameron; Cunningham, Mary Kathleen; Dawson, John David; Dickens, William Thomas (Box 78, Folder 215-223)
  - Writings of: Eckerstorfer, Bernhard A.; Ellingsen, Mark; Erickson, John H.; Erwin, Robert Guy; Fackre, Gabriel (Box 79, Folder 224-229)
  - Writings of: Field, L.; Forde, Gerhard O.; Gardella, Peter; Gavrilkin, Konstantin (Box 80, Folder 230-235)
  - Writings of: Goleman, Lary A.; Grieb, A. Katherine; Hollinger, David A.; Hütter, Reinhard; Jenson, Robert; Jodock, Darrell; Keck, Leander E.; Kee, Howard Clark; Kelsey, David H.; Kobler, John F.; Koch, George J.; Lakeland, Paul; Martin, Frederick N. (Box 81, Folder 236-248)
  - Writings of: Martyn, Louis; McCue, James; McFague, Sallie; McFarland, Ian A.; Neville, Robert; Oakes, Edward T.; Ochs, Peter; Ollenburger, Ben C.; Outka, Gene; Pelikan, Jaroslav (Box 82, Folder 249-259)
  - Writings of: Piepkorn, Arthur; Reno, R. R.; Rouner, Andrew; Shippee, Arthur; Stout, Jeffrey; Studer, James N.; Sumner, George; Turner, Philip; Uhlig, Valerie M.; Weaver, J. Denny; Wehrwein, George and Austin; Wilken, Robert; Wolterstorff, Nicholas; Woolverton, John F.; Wyschogrod, Michael (Box 83, Folder 260-275)
  - Thesis by Andreas Eckerstorfer: "The Postliberal Theology of George Lindbeck and Its Catholic Reception", 1995 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - "Reflections on the Retirement of Julian Hartt" by Wm. Muehl (?), n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Writings of: Klauspeter Blaser, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 5)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1940-2004; Series X
  - Original files
    - Articles regarding Lindbeck: "Re-Viewing Vatican II: An Interview with George A. Lindbeck" by George Weigel, "A Third Way in Theology?" by Gary Darrien in Christian Century, 1994-2001 (Box 55, Folder 1297)
    - Articles regarding Lindbeck: "Facing Unity - A conversation with George A. Lindbeck" in Lutheran Partners and newspaper article in CPH Commentator, 1966, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 1311)
    - Retirement keepsake printed by Guy Erwin, 1993 (Box 56, Folder 1304)
    - Awards and Fellowships (Box 55, Folder 1290-1291)
    - Budgets, nd (Box 55, Folder 1292)
    - Curriculum Vitae, nd (Box 55, Folder 1293)
    - Relatives, nd (Box 55, Folder 1294-1295)
    - Miscellaneous, nd (Box 55, Folder 1296)
  - Addendum
    - Family history, incl. journals and pamphlets of J. W. Lindbeck (GL's father) and deaths of GL's parents, 1957-1977, n. d. (Box 84, Folder 276-279)
    - Family - writings of Kristen Lindbeck (GL's daughter), 1992 (Box 84, Folder 280)
    - Appointment books, 1971-1994 (Box 84, Folder 281-282)
    - Personal diaries, 1963, 1968, 1987-1999 (Box 85, Folder 283-287)
    - China journal, 1996-2001 (Box 86, Folder 288)
    - Photographs of GL, family, and friends, 1920s-1990s (Box 86, Folder 289)
    - Portraits of GL, n. d. (Box 86, Folder 290)
    - Alumni citation from Greater Gustavus Association, honorary degree and citation from University of Notre Dame, honorary degree and citation from Virginia Theological Seminary, 1965, 1966, 1997 (Box 87)
    - Citations and programs for honorary degrees including from The Jesuit School of Theology at Berkeley, Wilbur Cross Medal from Yale Graduate School Alumni Association, 1997-1998 (Box 86, Folder 291)
    - Wartburg Seminary honorary degree, 2000 (Box 86, Folder 292)
    - Certificate for Yale Professor Emeritus distinction, 1993 (Box 86, Folder 293)
    - Paul Wattson Christian Unity Award program, 2000 (Box 86, Folder 294)
    - Yale Alumni Awards program, 2004 (Box 86, Folder 295)
    - Memorabilia - including gifts from China trip, 1996, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 296-297)
    - D.D. citation from Uppsala College, 1984 (Box 90, Folder 24)